





### **PUBLICATIONS**

## Neural-PBIR Reconstruction of Shape, Material, and Illumination

under review

Cheng Sun\*, Guangyan Cai\*, Zhengqin Li, Kai Yan, Cheng Zhang, Carl Marshall, Jia-Bin Huang, Shuang Zhao, Zhao Dong

[Paper], [Code]

## Data Efficient 3D Learner via Knowledge Transferred from 2D Model

ECCV 2022

Ping-Chung Yu, Cheng Sun, Min Sun

[Paper], [Code]

### **Multiview Regenerative Morphing with Dual Flows**

ECCV 2022

Chih-Jung Tsai, Cheng Sun, Hwann-Tzong Chen

[Paper], [Code], [Project page]

# Direct Voxel Grid Optimization: Super-fast Convergence for Radiance Fields Reconstruction CVPR 2022 (oral)

Cheng Sun, Min Sun, Hwann-Tzong Chen

[Paper], [Code], [Project page]

3D scene reconstruction from multiple images. Achieved <u>state-of-the-art quality</u> with <u>more than 100 times speedup</u> in optimization time (10–20+ hrs to 5 mins per scene).

### Specialize and Fuse: Pyramid Output Representation for Semantic Segmentation

ICCV 2021

Chi-Wei Hsiao\*, Cheng Sun\*, Hwann-Tzong Chen, Min Sun

[Paper]

### HoHoNet: 360 Indoor Holistic Understanding with Latent Horizontal Features

CVPR 2021

Cheng Sun, Min Sun, Hwann-Tzong Chen

[Paper], [Code]

## Indoor Panorama Planar 3D Reconstruction via Divide and Conquer

CVPR 2021 (oral)

Cheng Sun, Chi-Wei Hsiao, Ning-Hsu Wang, Min Sun, Hwann-Tzong Chen

[Paper], [Code]

## HorizonNet: Learning Room Layout with 1D Representation and Pano Stretch Data Augmentation CVPR 2019

Cheng Sun, Chi-Wei Hsiao, Min Sun, Hwann-Tzong Chen

[Paper], [Code]

Room layout reconstruction from a 360 image. Proposed a novel layout format which now have been widely adopted in this task.

## **EDUCATION**

## **National Tsing Hua University**

Sep 2018 - Sep 2023 (expected)

Ph.D. in Institute of Information System and Application

GPA: 4.28 / 4.3

Advisors: Prof. Hwann-Tzong Chen and Prof. Min Sun.

#### **National Chiao Tung University**

Aug 2014 - Jan 2018

B.S. in Computer Science

GPA: 3.87 / 4.0

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Computer Vision Research Intern, Aeolus Robotics**

Feb 2023 - now

Indoor 3D reconstruction from robot sensor / Generic 3D semantic and instance segmentation

## Research Scientist Intern, Meta Reality Labs

June 2022 - Dec 2022

Object 3D reconstruction from color video / PBR material estimation / Lighting estimation

### **AWARD**

## Phi Tau Phi Scholastic Honor Society Honorary Membership

*Apr 2023* 

**Google Conference Scholarships** 

*May 2022* 

ASUS Intelligent Cloud Services (AICS) Ph.D. Scholarship

Sep 2020 - Apr 2022

Novatek M.S. Scholarship

Aug 2019 - July 2020